<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Design | Rambling Raptors]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ramblingraptors.com/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ramblingraptors.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-23T23:55:20-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.ramblingraptors.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex Stephen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favicons]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ramblingraptors.com/blog/2013/03/13/favicons/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-13T00:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.ramblingraptors.com/blog/2013/03/13/favicons</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>They're really the most utilized, least appreciated part of a good website. The favicon. Being visual creatures, the favicon is how we quickly sort tabs. They're close to (if not) the most important branding statement of a website, yet nobody ever gives them their due credit. Being the near narcissist I am, I'd like to dedicate some space to the only decent design work I've ever done and where the inspiration came from.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First, I'd like to mention how complex the favicon has become. Initially, the favicon was a 16x16 icon file. Then came the png icons, which can use basically any size. Then comes the iOS devices, which of course need a iPhone and iPad icon (technically both retina and non-retina). Finally, Windows 8 comes into the mix with a tile icon. That's 5 files if you're following.</p>

<p>Props to <a href="http://www.jonathantneal.com/blog/understand-the-favicon/">this amazing article</a> for the help and the history.</p>

<p>Now, the favicon.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/favicon.png" title="'Ain't she beautiful?'" ></p>

<p>There were two distinct obstacles that had to be overcome. First, my design chops. Second, the amount of information that could be contained in 256 pixels. And third, my design chops. The inspiration came from genetics. Back in high school, most people learn about genetics in a high school biology class. When they learn about dominant and recessive genes, they associate them with R and r respectively. That kinda dawned on me. When a person has both a dominant and recessive gene, their genotype is displayed as Rr. Typographically, it looks really neat with the right font. And plus there's a very profound statement about bridging the dichotomy between life and programming... or something like that. As soon as I have it solidified, that'll be my new reason.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
